Guide to the Harvey Fierstein Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harvey Fierstein papers
1896-2015
1971-2006
MS 1864
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
45.48
(134 boxes) and 10.6 gigabytes
The collection documents Harvey Fierstein as author, actor, and gay activist. The papers include scripts, professional correspondence, publicity materials, clippings, legal documents, scrapbooks, photographs, audio recordings, and videotapes.
Fierstein, Harvey, 1954-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
The computer files are unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu. The request should outline the scope and purpose of the research project, why the researcher believes the material is relevant to their project, and contact information. If possible the request should also include a list of specific material of interest including collection, box, and folder numbers (or folder descriptions if folders are not numbered). The review may take several weeks.
Custodial History
Gift of Harvey Fierstein, 2005, 2006, 2008, 2010, and 2017.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series and four additions: I. Writings, 1972-2005. II. Performances, 1966-2006. III. Topical, 1896, 1919-2005 (inclusive), 1967-2005 (bulk). IV. Clippings, 1971-2005. V. Audiovisual, 1966-2004.
Scope and Contents
The collection primarily documents the professional career of Harvey Fierstein as noted writer and performer. Files of writings, topical files, clippings, and audiovisual materials additionally illuminate the theater industry as a whole, particularly the production of plays ranging from independent, low-budget productions to major theatrical endeavors, and how the media has depicted a prominent gay artist in the late twentieth century. There is also documentation related to the political and social causes in which Fierstein has been involved.
Biographical / Historical
Harvey Fierstein, award-winning playwright, actor and gay rights activist, was born on June 6, 1954, in Brooklyn, New York. He received his B.F.A. from the Pratt Institute in 1973. Aware of his sexuality as a young man, he appeared as a female impersonator in Manhattan nightclubs in his early teens. His career as an actor began in 1971 when he had the lead role as a lesbian maid in Andy Warhol's Pork. His first play, In Search of the Cobra Jewels, was produced in 1973. The International Stud, the first of three plays that eventually comprised the Torch Song Trilogy, was produced in 1976. Followed by Fugue in a Nursery and Widows and Children First, the trilogy won two Tonys, and was made into a movie, starring Fierstein, in 1988. Fierstein also won Tonys for his book for the musical La Cage aux Folles and for his role in the Broadway production of Hairspray. He has appeared in more than ten movies, and his voice has been featured on The Simpsons television show and in the Disney animated film, Legends of Mulan. His appearances on television include the 1994-1995 series, Daddy's Girls, and Family Guy.
Female impersonators; Gay authors; Gay dramatists; Gays and the performing arts; Homosexuality in motion pictures; Off-Broadway theater; LGBTQ resource; Fierstein, Harvey, 1954-
- Writings, 1972-2005; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The series is arranged alphabetically by title. Files include scripts (arranged chronologically within title), clippings, photographs, contracts, programs, and promotional material relating to Fierstein's work as an author of Broadway plays, movie screenplays, and television scripts. It is probable that some of the titles herein were not published or produced. Folder headings are largely derived from Fierstein's own titles.
  - All for You [formerly Frankie and Johnny Were Lovers], 1986, 1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - All My Children, 2003 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amos and Andy
    General note
    See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 41
  - Becoming a Woman, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bennington address, 1992 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Big Cutie in Little Italy
    - Pitch, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Scripts
      - 1st draft, 2000 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Unidentified draft, 2000 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Unidentified draft, 2001 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burly Babs Burrito Bar [script-1st draft], 1995 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - La Cage aux Folles
    - General, 1983-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Audio recording
      General
      See: Series V. Audiovisual, 1966-2004 Box 57
    - Clippings and printed materials, 1983-1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 11 - 12)
    - Copyright on book, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Poiret arbitration
      - General, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 14 - 16)
      - Briefs, 1985 August (Box 2, Folder 17 - 19)
      - Pre-trial materials, 1985 January (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Settlement, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21 - 23)
    - Programs, 1983, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Rehearsal, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Revival
      - Notes, 2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Rehearsal script, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Revisions, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Scrapbook, 1982-1985, undated (Box 4)
    - Scripts
      - Preliminary outline, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - 2nd draft, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - 3rd draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Printed scripts, 1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 32 - 33)
      - Miscellaneous drafts, 1984-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Tickets/stubs, 1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Cannibals Just Don't Know No Better
    - Play
      - Business-notes, 1976-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
        See also: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 147
      - Script, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Screenplay [script], 1993 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - A Catered Affair
    - Legal, 2002 September (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Script [1st draft], 2005 July 21 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Common Ground
    - Amos and Andy [script], 1999 January 24 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Clippings and printed materials, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Publicity, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Scripts
      - 2nd draft, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Unidentified draft, 1999 August (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - Unidentified draft, 1999 September (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - A Coney Island Spookhouse
    See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 160
  - The Culture of Disease, New York Times, 2003 July-August (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - The Cure [proposal], 1980 March (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Don't Ask, Don't Tell Who's Naughty or Nice [speech with related materials], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - The Eighth Street Block Association [proposal], 1980 March (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Flatbush Tosca
    - General, 1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Music, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Scripts, 1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 53 - 54)
  - Forget Him
    - General, 1982, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Scripts, 1981-1982, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 56 - 57)
  - Formerly the Park Girls
    See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 101
  - Frankie and Johnny Were Lovers
    See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 1
  - Freaky Pussy
    - General, 1974, 1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Audio recording (Box 58)
      See: Series V. Audiovisual, 1966-2004 Box 58
    - Scripts, 1974, 1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Granny Goose, 1979 July 21 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Harvey
    See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 99 - 100
  - Haunted Host [by Robert Patrick, but later revised by Fierstein and others]
    - Boston production [not associated with Fierstein's revised version], 1975-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 61 - 62)
    - Clippings, 1991, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - La Mama production, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Photographs, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Programs and publicity, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Scrapbook, 1976, 1991, undated (Box 4)
      Related Materials
      See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Box 4
    - Scripts
      - Correspondence with Robert Patrick [regarding scripts], 1990 November-1991 Jul, undated (Box 8, Folder 68)
      - 1st Edit, 1990 November (Box 8, Folder 69 - 71)
      - La Mama version, undated (Box 8, Folder 72)
      - Unidentified version, undated (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - In Search of the Cobra Jewels, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 9, Folder 74)
    See also: Series V. Audiovisual, 1966-2004 Box 60
  - In the Absence of Angels [1st draft], 1992 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - In the Shadow of the Cyclone [scenario for a screenplay], 1999 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Just Folks
    - Correspondence, 1990 Apr, August (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Scripts
      - 1st drafts, 1990 May-July (Box 9, Folder 78)
      - Revised 1st draft, 1990 August (Box 9, Folder 79)
      - 2nd draft, 1990 September (Box 9, Folder 79)
      - Revised 2nd drafts, 1990 October-1991 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Kaddish and Old Men [scenario], 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Lady, 1992, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Legs Diamond
    - General, 1987-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Legal/financial, 1987-1993, undated (Box 10, Folder 84 - 86)
    - Scrapbook, 1988, undated (Box 4)
    - Scripts
      - 1st drafts, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 87 - 88)
      - 2nd draft, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 89)
      - Miscellaneous drafts, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 90 - 92)
  - Luncheonette
    See: Series I. Writings, 1972-2005 Folder 182
  - La Merman [speech], 1991 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Michael, undated (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Mother, undated (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Musical scores and lyrics, 1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - A Mystery for Our Times, TV Guide, 1993, undated (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Not on My Network You Don't, 1992 January (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Now You're Cookin' [also known as Harvey; scripts], 1991, undated (Box 11, Folder 99 - 100)
  - The Park Girls [also known as Formerly the Park Girls and Singing Sisters]
    - General, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Legal, 1985-1986, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Scripts
      - 1st drafts, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 104 - 107)
      - 1st draft with notes, 1985 November (Box 12, Folder 108)
      - 2nd draft, 1986 March (Box 13, Folder 109)
      - Unidentified drafts, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 110 - 111)
  - Plucked
    - General, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - Scripts
      - 1st rough draft, 1993 October (Box 13, Folder 113)
      - 1st draft, 1993 November (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Rescue Me, 1997 May (Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Safe Sex trilogy
    - General, 1985-1992 (Box 13, Folder 116 - 119)
    - Book, 1987-1991 (Box 14, Folder 120)
    - Clippings and printed materials, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 121)
    - Copyrights [includes scripts of Torch Song Trilogy and Forget Him], 1986-1990 (Box 14, Folder 122 - 123)
    - HBO Showcase, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - La Mama, 1987, undated (Box 14, Folder 125)
    - Manchester, England production, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - Manny and Jake
      - Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 127)
      - Script [1st draft], 1986 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - On Tidy Endings
      - Film
        - General, 1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 129 - 130)
        - Clippings and printed materials, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 131)
        - Reviews, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 132)
        - Scripts
          - 1st draft, 1988 February 7 (Box 15, Folder 133)
          - 1st draft with changes, 1988 February 15 (Box 15, Folder 134)
      - Play
        - Notes, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 135)
        - Spanish translation, 1994 March 30 (Box 15, Folder 136)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Safe Sex [script-1st draft], 1986 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - The Schubert Organization, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 139 - 140)
    - Scrapbook and collage, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Scripts
      - Unidentified drafts, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 141 - 142)
      - Sound/lighting script, undated (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Second Hand Joe's
    - Scripts
      - 1st rough draft, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 144)
      - 1st draft, 1993 August (Box 15, Folder 145)
      - 1st draft with revisions, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 146)
  - A Second Opinion [scripts], 1978 (Box 16, Folder 147)
  - Shepard, Matthew article and speech, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Singing Sisters
  - The Sissy Duckling
    - General, 1999-2002, undated (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Scripts
      - 3rd draft, 1998 May 3 (Box 16, Folder 150)
      - Shooting script, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 151)
      - Miscellaneous drafts, 1999-2001 (Box 16, Folder 152)
      - Page breaks, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 153)
      - Storyline, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - The Snow Queen
    - General, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - Scenario, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    - Script [1st draft], 1992 March (Box 16, Folder 157)
    - Storyline, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - Songs for Dead Children [script], 1990 (Box 16, Folder 159)
  - Spookhouse
    - General, 1980-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - Australia production, 1986, undated (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - Legal, 1983-1987 (Box 16, Folder 162)
    - Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 163)
    - Reading, undated (Box 17, Folder 164)
    - San Francisco production, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 165)
    - Scripts
      - Scenario, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 166)
      - Unidentified drafts
        - 1980 (Box 17, Folder 167)
        - 1981 (Box 17, Folder 168 - 169)
        - 1982 (Box 17, Folder 170)
        - 1984 (Box 17, Folder 171 - 175)
        - 1986 (Box 18, Folder 176)
        - 1987 (Box 18, Folder 177 - 178)
        - n.d. (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - Stanley's After Hours Joint, 1974, undated (Box 18, Folder 180)
  - Stella, undated (Box 18, Folder 181)
  - Subway [scripts], undated (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - This is Not Going to be Pretty
    - Clippings
      - Regarding compact disc, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 183)
      - Stand-up performances, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 184)
    - European tour, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 185)
    - Publicity, undated (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Torch Song Trilogy
    - General, 1978-1982, undated (Box 18, Folder 187 - 188)
    - Awards
      - Friends of the Center, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 189)
      - Los Angeles Drama Critics Circle plaque, 1983 (Box 19)
      - Tony, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 190 - 193)
    - Book, 1980-1982, undated (Box 20, Folder 194)
    - Clippings and printed materials, 1978-1991, undated (Box 20, Folder 195 - 199)
    - Clippings and printed materials, 1978-1991, undated (Box 21, Folder 200 - 207)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1986, undated (Box 22, Folder 208 - 213)
    - Fugue in a Nursery
      - General, 1978-1982, undated (Box 22, Folder 214 - 217)
      - Clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 218)
      - Correspondence, 1974, 1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 219)
      - Scripts
        - General, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 220)
        - 1st draft, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 221)
    - The International Stud
      - General, 1976-1981 (Box 23, Folder 222)
      - Clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 23, Folder 223 - 224)
      - Los Angeles production, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 225 - 226)
      - Minneapolis production, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 227)
      - San Francisco production, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 228)
      - Scripts
        - Monologue, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 229)
        - 1st draft, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 230)
        - Unidentified draft, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 231)
      - Slides [with contact sheets], undated (Box 24, Folder 232)
      - South Africa production, 1978-1981 (Box 24, Folder 233)
    - Legal
      - General, 1981-1984 (Box 24, Folder 234)
      - Agreements, 1982-1988 (Box 24, Folder 235 - 237)
      - Financial, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 238)
      - Kisch, John Duke, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 239)
      - Maxwell, Mitchell, 1979-1983 (Box 24, Folder 240 - 242)
    - London production, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 243)
    - Movie
      - General, 1988-1992 (Box 25, Folder 244 - 247)
      - Clippings, 1988-1991 (Box 25, Folder 248 - 253)
      - Clippings, 1988-1991 (Box 26, Folder 254 - 257)
      - Legal
        - General, 1985-1989 (Box 26, Folder 258 - 263)
        - Agreements, 1988-1989 (Box 27, Folder 264 - 269)
        - Fierstein v New Line, et al., 1986-1993 (Box 28, Folder 270 - 272)
        - Financial, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 273 - 275)
        - Screenplay rights, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 276)
      - Photographs, 1988, undated (Box 28, Folder 277)
      - Print ad tests, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 278)
      - Production
        - Call sheets, 1988 May-July (Box 29, Folder 279)
        - Schedule, 1988 May 13-June 1 (Box 29, Folder 280 - 281)
      - Scripts
        - 1st drafts
          - 1984 Jul 19 (Box 29, Folder 282 - 284)
          - 1984 Aug (Box 29, Folder 285 - 287)
        - Draft 1B, 1984 August (Box 30, Folder 288)
        - 2nd drafts, 1986 November (Box 30, Folder 289 - 290)
        - 3rd drafts, 1988 January (Box 30, Folder 291 - 293)
        - 5th drafts, 1988 February (Box 31, Folder 294 - 295)
      - Television
        - General, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 296)
        - Television cuts, 1991-1992 (Box 31, Folder 297)
      - Tote bag, undated (Box 32)
    - National Research Group, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 298)
    - Photographs, 1978, 1982, undated (Box 33, Folder 299 - 300)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 34)
    - Programs, 1982-1988 (Box 35, Folder 301 - 302)
    - Promotional materials, 1983, undated (Box 35, Folder 303)
    - Provincetown, Massachusetts production, 1999 (Box 35, Folder 304)
    - Scrapbooks, 1979-1988, undated (Box 36–37)
    - Scripts
      - General, 1978-1979, 1983 April 1, undated (Box 38, Folder 305 - 306)
      - French translation of, undated (Box 38, Folder 307)
    - Slides, undated (Box 38, Folder 308)
    - Spain production, 1983, undated (Box 38, Folder 309)
    - Sweden production, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 310)
    - Widows and Children First
      - Clippings and printed materials, 1979-1980, undated (Box 39, Folder 311)
      - Contract, 1979 October 17 (Box 39, Folder 312)
      - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 313)
      - Ithaca, New York production, 1979-1980 (Box 39, Folder 314)
      - Offering, 1980, undated (Box 39, Folder 315)
      - Phoenix production, 1981-1982, undated (Box 39, Folder 316)
      - Photographs, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 317)
      - Press releases, 1979, undated (Box 39, Folder 318)
      - Programs and promotional, 1979, undated (Box 39, Folder 319)
      - Scripts
        - General, 1979, undated (Box 39, Folder 320)
        - 1st draft, undated (Box 39, Folder 321)
        - Unidentified drafts, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 322)
  - Union Street [pilot script], 1992 August (Box 40, Folder 323)
  - The Very Last Camp, undated (Box 40, Folder 324)
  - What Makes Me Angry, National Lampoon, undated (Box 40, Folder 325)
  - Articles, short stories, poetry, and untitled, 1978-2003, undated (Box 40, Folder 326 - 327)
- Performances, 1966-2006; Series II
  The series contains materials relating to plays, musicals, and television shows in which Fierstein performed but did not write. Materials are arranged alphabetically, primarily by title, and include clippings, correspondence, programs, publicity materials, and scripts. Folder headings are largely derived from Fierstein's own folders.
  - Americka Cleopatra, 1972, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Cheers, "Rebecca's Lover...Not", 1992 February (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Christopher at Sheridan Squared, 1971, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Daddy's Girls [clippings], 1994 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Death to Smoochy, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - The Dirtiest Show in Town, 1977, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Jeckyll and Ms. Hyde, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - The Dudley Moore Project, 1994 April 19 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Fiddler on the Roof
    - General, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 2004-2005 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2004-2006, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Programs and publicity, 2004-2005, undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Gallery Players-various plays, 1970-1971, undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Garbo Talks, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Hairspray
    - General, 2001-2003, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Audio recording-rehearsal, Circa 2001-circa 2004 (Box 59)
      See: Series V. Audiovisual, 1966-2004 Box 59
    - Clippings, 2002-2006, undated (Box 42, Folder 16 - 21)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 2001-2002, undated (Box 43, Folder 22 - 24)
      - Farewell cards, 2004, undated (Box 43, Folder 25 - 27)
    - Photographs, 2002, undated (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - Scrapbooks, 2001-2004, undated (Box 44–45)
    - Scripts
      - First drafts
        - Rough, 2002 March 28 (Box 46, Folder 29)
        - Revised, 2002 April 1 (Box 46, Folder 30)
      - Score, undated (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Idols [clippings], 1974 January-March (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Kitchenette, 1971-1972, undated (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - The Legend of Mulan, 1995, undated (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - The Little Matchgirl Makes it Big, 1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - One Man's Religion and The Pinotti Papers, 1975, undated (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - The Pioneer and Pro-Game [includes other Megan Terry materials], 1966-1975, undated (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - Playbirth, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Playhouse of the Ridiculous [Persia and Satyricon], undated (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - Pork, 1971, undated (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - Pouf Positive [scripts], undated (Box 46, Folder 41)
  - Prometheus Bound, 1972-1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 42)
  - Queen of Greece, 1973-1974, undated (Box 46, Folder 43)
  - Rags to Riches to Rags, undated (Box 46, Folder 44)
  - Rivals, 1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 45)
  - The Secret Place, 1975, undated (Box 46, Folder 46)
  - The Silver Bee, undated (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - Theatre of the Last Continent [Vinyl Visits an FM Station and Boy on the Straight-Back Chair], undated (Box 46, Folder 48)
  - Those Two
    - General, 1993, undated (Box 46, Folder 49)
    - Scripts
      - 2nd draft, 1993 March 10 (Box 46, Folder 50)
      - Final draft, 1992 Nov, 1993 March (Box 46, Folder 51 - 52)
      - Table draft, undated (Box 46, Folder 53)
  - Trojan Woman, 1972-1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 54)
  - The Two Noble Kinsmen, 1973, 1976, undated (Box 46, Folder 55)
  - White Cargo', undated (Box 46, Folder 56)
  - Xircus! The Private Life of Jesus Christ, 1971, undated (Box 46, Folder 57)
  - oo [infinity sign], 1974, undated (Box 46, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous [mostly publicity materials], 1988, undated (Box 46, Folder 59)
- Topical, 1896-2005 (inclusive), 1967-2005 (bulk); Series III
  The series is arranged alphabetically. Files relate to causes for which Fierstein has advocated, the theater industry in general, and there is a small amount of personal and biographical material on Fierstein. Plays are comprised of three scripts, which were written by others and in which Fierstein did not act. Collected musical scores, dating as early as 1896, are filed under music. Folder headings are largely derived from Fierstein's own folders.
  - AIDS, 1987, 2003, 2005, undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Artwork, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Awards
    - General, 1982-2003 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Emmy nominations, 1992, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 2000-2001 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - CBS, 1983-1991, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Disney-Devito project, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Fierstein, Harvey
    - Biographical, 1994-1995, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)